# **Alexandre TANGUY**

#### **Engineering manager**

Head of IT technical teams and projects with a network and security engineer background. What I (love to) do: management of teams, encouraging excellence, lead by example, being data-driven and customer-oriented.

What I am not: a software engineer.







## Who am I and what am I looking for?

After 8 years in the tech field as a network and security engineer, where I learned lots of things and grow up as an engineer and a human being, I understood that I was happier and better leading a team and helping its members to grow. I seized the opportuny offered by OVHcloud to manage one and then two teams of software engineers.

Today, I love this mission and I am eager to continue in a challenging environment with

### ■ Professional experience

**Engineering Manager** @ OVHcloud (January 2020 - Present)

Team leader of the Network Data squad, composed of the Network Observability and the Network IPAM teams. 1. Monitoring tens of thousands of network devices: 50M+ timeseries / 1M+ datapoint per seconds / 25M+ log messages per day 2. Managing around 4.5M public IP addresses in 3 RIR (RIPE, ARIN, APNIC)

- Point of contact for other teams and PU, for Network observability and IP related topics
- Follow-up on projects
- Creation of roadmaps with Program managers support
- Agile methodology implementation and animation: sprint planning, daily, sprint review, retrospectives, etc.

Network Engineer @ OVHcloud (Bordeaux) (Mars 2018 - January 2020)

Member of the Network Design Datacenter team, I was in charge of the vRack product design and projects.

- In charge of the design of network products
- In charge of R&D on some projects
- Technologies: BGP, VXLAN, ECMP, Cisco and Arista devices

**Network and Security Engineer** @ Cdiscount (Bordeaux) (December 2015 - Mars 2018) Member of the Security team during 1 year and then moved to the SRE team for 1 year (internal move-up).

- In charge of the network and security infrastructure operations (L3)
- In charge of the improvement and evolution of the network and security infrastructure, working in/with the Security team
- Part of the PCIDSS / SOX compliance and annual certification
- **Technologies:** Cisco ACI, Checkpoint firewalls, F5 loadbalancers, Citrix Netscaler, RIP/OSPF/VLAN

Network and Security Engineer @ Rothschild & Co (Paris, mission via Owentis) (February 2015 - November 2015)

Member of the Network and Security team, as a project lead of the "IT migration of internal ressources to HP Enterprises", and as Net/Sec engineer.

- In charge of the network and security operations (support of the team lead)
- Point of contact and follow-up of the externalisation project

**Network and Security Engineer** @ Société Générale (Paris, mission via Owentis) (January 2013 - February 2015)

Member of one of the Network and Security team in charge of FranFinance and La Banque Postale Financement.

- In charge of infrastructure operations (75%)
- In charge of infrastructure improvement and migration projects (25%)

**Network and Security Engineer** @ Crédit Agricole - CA Technologies & Services (Lyon, internship) (July 2011 - November 2012) Internship and then "contrat de professionnalisation"

- Assistant of the project lead of the "Migration X25" project
- Network L3 operations

## ■ Education and languages

- January 2015: CCNA v2 certification (200-120). Result: 958/1000
- 2012: TOEIC 940/990
- 2007 2012: SUPINFO Engineer in IT technologies (french Bac+5 Master II niveau 1)
- June 2007: BAC S specialty mathematics (Baccalauréat Scientifique spécialité Mathématiques)

#### Activities and interests

- **Hobbies**: reading (a lot: sci-fi, fantasy, classical, history), photography, music listening (jazz and electronic)
- Sports: climbing/bouldering, running, cycling, hiking
- **Volunteering**: member of the french Red-Cross (Croix-Rouge française) from 2013 to 2015 as a rescuer (PSE2) and local director

Volunteering

**TBC**